Jim Withington

503-309-4228 jamesrwithington@gmail.com 1642 SE Ash Street Portland, OR 97214

Profile

Experienced coaching, mentoring, and online learning professional. Professional development specialist with extensive experience facilitating in-house training and mentoring colleagues. Skilled writer experienced in working with extremely short deadlines. Quick learner focused on continual self-improvement. Web developer learning CSS, Javascript, and Rails.

Experience

CUSTOMER SUCCESS COORDINATOR, TREEHOUSE; PORTLAND, OR - 2015

As primary leads captain, drove month-over-month B2B revenue growth through targeted email. Led demos and held phone calls designed to show value to prospective customers. Documented processes as part of new Treehouse for Organizations team. Built relationships with new customers through quick, thorough, and concise support.

HARVEST EXPERT, HARVEST; REMOTE - 2014

Helped current, new, and prospective Harvest customers with questions and concerns by phone, email, Zendesk, and other means.

SENIOR LEAD MENTOR, PEARSON EDUCATION; REMOTE – 2013-2014

Led a distributed team of mentors to help them deliver life-altering mentoring meetings to first-year college students taking developmental courses. Advised on ways to train, improve, and evaluate mentors while creating a brand new program.

ONLINE SUPPORT SPECIALIST/INSTRUCTOR, SPOON RIVER COLLEGE; CANTON, IL - 2011-2013

Provided one-on-one support for college students through an online submission system. Evaluated and revised student-facing orientation materials.

COACH, TRAINER, AND MENTOR, INSIDETRACK; PORTLAND, OR - 2007-2011

Onboarded and trained new employees. Managed a coaching load of approximately 100 students per 8-week session by independently balancing multiple priorities and performance metrics. Consistently exceeded retention goals by 2-10%.

Education

Code Oregon / Treehouse : Rails Developer track, 2014 Columbia College, Chicago, IL – MA Interdisciplinary Arts, 2002 Northwestern University, Evanston, IL – BS Education and Social Policy, 2000

Skills

Computer: Mac OS X, Salesforce, Markdown, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Ruby Other: Evaluative observation, writing, editing, life coaching, mentoring, teaching